Hey. Aron here, leave a message.
Hi Aron, Sonja here...again.
I know youre gonna be away this weekend, but ...
think about what we are going to play.
Please, we really have to decide we need to practice.
It will be fun, I promise.
And call mom, please. Because she worries ...
which you already knew. later A, bye.
It's Friday night.
April 25, 2003.
Im just entering Canyonlands.
Just me, the music and the night.
Love it.
SATURDAY
Blue John Canyon.
The guidebook says: 4.5 hours until the Big Dropper.
I want to take 45 minutes off of that.
I think we opmoeten side.
And if we proceed this way ...
Youre doing Blue John too? - No, were headed for the Dome.
But I think we are lost. - She's lost.
Hang on.
Lets see this.
You are ... here. - We are?
I knew that.
And the Dome is there.
I can take you that way if you like.
Sorry, Friday the 13th there.
I'm only a psychopath on weekdays. It's Saturday.
I cant take this off.
Aron. - Kristi.
Let me introduce you to my friend Megan.
Nice to meet you. - An honor.
What do you say? You're lost, I am the guide.
Why not. - Sure.
This way.
So you biked from Horseshoe? Is that like 32 km?
27 on the odometer.
I thought it was 27.6.
27.8. Actually.
Ah, You're one of those.
Not one of those. - Do you spend a lot of time out here?
Its my second home.
See? Theres the fork right there.
We totally missed that. - Glad we bumped into you.
What are the odds considering we're out here. - Exactly.
You're in the one place in America where you're guaranteed not to run into a weirdo...
And what happend?
Allright. So the guidebook says...
that the route is through here -but I know a better way.
The cool way.
Guaranteed, the best time you can have with your clothes on.
Although, it's better with your clothes off.
It is a bit of a climb. - We climb.
And a bit of a squeeze. - We squeeze.
So you get us all the way here and then you tell us you're not a guide ...
Well no, I'm an engineer.
But this is what I really want to do.
Wonderful. I always wanted to be a supermodel, but ...
I don't think thats really gonna work.
Jesus. What if these things move? - They've been here for millions of years. They're not gonna move.
Oh sure they will. - What?
Everything's moving all the time. Just hope not today.
Great.
All you've got to remember, is that everything will be okay.
My God!
Aron, are you okay?
Listen to the guy, he's fine.
He is bad shit. You're bad shit!
Come on. You've gotta come down here.
Trust me. - Trust you? I'll kill you Aron Ralston.
Oh, please, you love this.
Nice job!
Megan, you're missing it. - It's amazing.
Fuck. - Just jump, Megan.
Are you okay? - Nice job.
We've got to do it again. - Again?
Camera.
So, Blue John ...
is actually named after Butch Cassidy's cook.
From Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid.
And they would hide out in these canyons, I guess,
but would also run wild horses into here and trap them at the end of the canyon ...
and that's how they caught the horses.
Another picture before I go? - Yes.
Ready?
One, two, three ...
Will I ever see you again? - That depends, do you party?
Do I party? Yes, sometimes.
Tomorrow we're throwing a party, if you want to come.
Yeah, you shoud come by for a beer. - OK, where am I going?
It is 32 km away, near Green River. Behind the old motel.
There will be a huge inflatable Scooby-Doo. Can't miss it.
Good to meet you. - Bye.
Scooby-Doo.
Rock on.
You think he's actually gonna show up?
I don't think we figured in his day at all.
You liked him.
127 HOURS
This is insane.
Move this fucking rock.
Please.
Kristi! Megan!
Just think.
Shit.
Sweet.
Knife's dull.
SUNDAY
Look at the size of this. How the fuck did this get here?
Hi, buddy.
Here we go.
It's 03:05.
Sunday, April 27, 2003.
This marks 24 hours...
of being stuck in Blue John Canyon. Just before the junction for the Big Drop.
My name is Aron Ralston. My parents are ...
Donna and Larry Ralston. From Englewood Colorado.
Whoever finds this, can keep the recorder ...
but please get in touch with my parents and give them this tape.
I would appreciate it.
I was descending Blue John yesterday ...
when this chalkstone came loose ...
and rolled onto my arm.
Now it's stuck.
The arm has a blue-gray color.
It's been without circulation for 24 hours.
I think it's pretty well gone.
I'm low on food.
That's about 300-400 ml.
And that's it for water.
I'm in pretty deep doo here.
Hello?
Please, there's somebody down here.
Help! I am in the Canyon.
Please, help!
Help!
Down here. Help!
Don't lose it.
Aron ...
do not lose it.
Not bad.
Dinner.
Tomorrow we're throwing a party, if you want to come.
Have a beer.There will be a huge inflatable Scooby-Doo.
Scooby-Doo.
Cold cans.
Plastic cup.
Thank you.
Can I take a beer?
Won't mind if I do.
Aron here, leave a message.
Aron, it's mom.
I was hoping to catch you.
Are you there? Hello?
Okay. Nothing urgent.
Doug is in New York. So it will be a quiet weekend.
Call me.
Where are you going? - Don't know yet.
Right there, Brian. - Maybe Utah, maybe somewhere else.
Have a good one. - Always do.
Let's go.
MONDAY
It's freaking me out looking at myself.
Sorry, hope thats okay.
It's Monday.
Bummer, all day. I tried to set up this pulley.
All morning. But it did not work.
It was worth a try, but there is too much friction,
It's climbing rope, so theres too much stretch.
What I could use is 20 meters of static rope ...
9.8 millimeters.
Three or four pulleys, rack of carabiners, a sling, powerdrill ...
and a Pull Kit.
and eight burley men to do the hawling.
That should just about do it.
another 150 ml of water left.
That should keep me alive til tomorrow night.
If I'm lucky. I peeded twice.
almost pissed my pants.
My body's acting really wierd.
The second time I did it in the CamelBak.
It smells really bad.
But I'm sure it'll settle.
It's gotta be chilled, like Sauvignon Blanc.
No number twos.
Which should disappoint my insect friends.
They'll just have to wait.
Let's see, what else can I tell you?
There is this raven that comes every morning.
I clocked it at 08:17.
I'll film it for you tomorrow.
Every morning at 09:30 I get fifteen minutes sunlight.
Really nice.
I've been chipping away.
More to keep warm than anything.
I'm beginning to think that my hand is supporting the rock.
So what if I chip away a bit, it actually settles more.
I've found this great tourniquette.
It hasn't been very useful.
Listen! Don't buy the cheap made-in-China multitool.
I tried to find my Swiss Army knife.
This thing came free with a flashlight. The flashlight was a piece of shit too.
I kept it in my truck for emergencies.
I don't blame you, Mom.
It was a perfectly great stocking stuffer.
No way you could have ever known I'd get in this kind of trouble.
If you look back to it later the camera turned on?
You have to leave the camera with us when we wanna see something that you've made.
Good job, Hon.
That is really beautiful. - He's filming her now..
We can show this?
Go away.
We can't just watch it there.
Well done.
Way to go Sis.
Keep playing? - Yes honey, keep going.
I love you.
So ...
how do I get in?
What is the ...
combination?
If I told you ...
I'd have to kill you.
You've already killed me.
Combination? I think I have it.
Who's there?
Please.
TUESDAY
Good morning, everyone. It is seven o'clock here in Canyon Country USA.
This morning, on the boulder, we have a very special guest:
Self-proclaimed american superhero ...
Aron Ralston. Lets hear it for Aron.
It is a real pleasure to be here. Thank you. Thanks.
Can I say hi to my mom and dad?
Mom and Dad. Mustn't forget Mom and Dad. Right, Aron?
Yeah, that's right.
Hi mom, I'm really sorry I didn't answer the phone the other night.
If I had, I would have told you where I was going and then ...
I probably wouldn't be here. That's for sure.
But like I always say ...
Your supreme selfishness is our gain.
Thank you, Aron. Anyone else you'd like to say hi to?
Brian, at work.
I probably won't be making it in to work today.
Get a load of this guy. Wait.
We got a question coming in from another aron ...
...in Loser Canyon, Utah.
Aron asks: Am I right in thinking ...
that even if Brian from work notifies the police ...
they'll put a 24-hour hold on it before they file a missing persons report?
Which means you won't become officially missing ...
until miday Wednesday at the earliest.
You're right on the money there, Aron.
Which means, I'll probably be dead by then.
Aron from Loser Canyon, Utah.
How do you know so much? - I will tell you.
I volunteer for the rescue service.
I'm something of a, big fucking hard hero.
I can do everything on my own.
I do see.
Is it true that despite ...
or maybe because you're a fucking hard hero ...
You didn't tell anyone where you were going?
Yeah, that's absolutely correct.
Anyone? - Anyone.
Mom, Dad ...
I wanna take this time to tell you, the times we've spent together were awesome...
and I haven't appreciated you in my heart as I know that I could.
Mom, I love you ...
and I wish I had returned all your calls...
Ever.
I love you guys.
And I'll always be with you.
Pwnd!
WEDNESDAY
This is no Slurpy.
It's like a bag of piss.
I'm going again.
With clothes on.
Tell him. - We are very worried about you.
An advice for your choice of music.
If you "Fish are really rock and keeps on singing ... - Then you never get a girlfriend.
Maybe but I doubt it. - You are more or less clever.
From time to time.
This cannon ball is for you.
I'm going to test your theory whether it's better ...
with or without clothes.
Don't.
Please, don't.
Don't. - Ralston, rock on.
You don't even want me here, do you?
I'm gonna go, Aron.
Is that what you want?
It is, isn't it?
Come back.
You're gonna be so lonely, Aron.
46, 47, 48, 49 ...
50! Who remains is seen.
I'm holding on.
Time's moving really slowly.
My heart's beating really fast. It feels like it ...
it's beating three times as fast as it shold be.
So cold.
Blue John.
I love you.
Rana, I've been thinking about you, girl.
I know how I am. I've tried to do everything. Whatever it was ...
I tried. - where are you.
What are you guys doing here? Andy.
Tom. Hi, guys. Whats going on?
You look like the Hole in the Wall Gang.
Dorks.
Found you Aron.
Sis, sorry I won't be at your wedding.
I know that I promised to play.
That we play.
I'm sorry. I know it'll be a good one.
8:15, there's no raven. 8:20 ...
My raven didn't come.
I've been thinking.
Everything ...
... just comes together. - You're gonna be so lonely, Aron.
Have a good one. - Always do.
Later! - It' me.
Aron, it's mom.
I was hoping to catch you. - I chose this.
Doug is in New York. So it'll be a quiet weekend.
I chose all of this. - Call me.
This rock ...
This rock has been waiting for me my entire life.
I hate this rock!
It's entire life. Ever since it was a bit of meteorite.
A million billion years ago. - How the fuck did this get here?
There in space. It's been waiting ...
to come here.
Right, right here.
I've been moving towards it my whole life. The minute I was born.
Every breath I've taken, every action ...
has been leading me to this. A crack in the surface.
Come on.
Don't pass out.
Thank you.
Easy.
Easy. Come on.
Help me.
I need help.
I need some water. I was stuck in a crack.
Some water, please. I cut my arm off.
Please, some water.
Thank you.
Do you have a phone? - Yes, but no signal.
You should stop and rest. - No.
I better keep going.
Walk on. Run ahead.
Aron's premonition came true.
He met his wife Jessica three years later.
Their son, Leo, was born in February 2010.
Aron continued to climb and canyoneering do.
He always leaves a note where he goes.